[
    {
    "question": "Which of the following is a transport layer protocol?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " stream control transmission protocol",
        " internet control message protocol",
        " neighbor discovery protocol",
        " dynamic host configuration protocol"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "The Stream Control Transmission Protocol (SCTP) is a transport layer protocol used in networking system where streams of data are to be continuously transmitted between two connected network nodes. Some of the other transport layer protocols are RDP, RUDP, TCP, DCCP, UDP etc.",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Transport Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},
{
    "question": "Which one of the following is not a function of network layer?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " routing",
        " inter-networking",
        " congestion control",
        " error control"
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "In the OSI model, network layer is the third layer and it provides data routing paths for network communications. Error control is a function of the data link layer and the transport layer.",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Network  Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following routing algorithms can be used for network layer design?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " shortest path algorithm",
        " distance vector routing",
        " link state routing",
        " all of the mentioned"
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "The routing algorithm is what decides where a packet should go next. There are several routing techniques like shortest path algorithm, static and dynamic routing, decentralized routing, distance vector routing, link state routing, Hierarchical routing etc. The routing algorithms go hand in hand with the operations of all the routers in the networks. The routers are the main participants in these algorithms.",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Network  Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
,
{
    "question": "Which of the following is not correct in relation to multi-destination routing?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " is same as broadcast routing",
        " contains the list of all destinations",
        " data is not sent by packets",
        " there are multiple receivers"
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": " In multi-destination routing, there is more than one receiver and the route for each destination which is contained in a list of destinations is to be found by the routing algorithm. Multi-destination routing is also used in broadcasting.",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Network  Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
,
{
    "question": "Which of the following tasks is not done by data link layer?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " framing",
        " error control",
        " flow control",
        " channel coding"
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "Channel coding is the function of physical layer. Data link layer mainly deals with framing, error control and flow control. Data link layer is the layer where the packets are encapsulated into frames. ",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Data Link Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
},
{
    "question": "Which sublayer of the data link layer performs data link functions that depend upon the type of medium?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " logical link control sublayer",
        " media access control sublayer",
        " network interface control sublayer",
        " error control sublayer"
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "Media access control (MAC) deals with transmission of data packets to and from the network-interface card, and also to and from another remotely shared channel. The MAC sublayer also prevents collision using protocols like CSMA/CD. ",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Data Link Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
,
{
    "question": "Which of the following is a data link protocol?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " ethernet",
        " point to point protocol",
        " hdlc",
        " all of the mentioned"
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "There are many data link layer protocols. Some of them are SDLC (synchronous data link protocol), HDLC (High level data link control), SLIP (serial line interface protocol), PPP (Point to point protocol) etc. These protocols are used to provide the logical link control function of the Data Link Layer.",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Data Link Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
,
{
    "question": "Which of the following is the multiple access protocol for channel access control?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " CSMA/CD",
        " CSMA/CA",
        " Both CSMA/CD & CSMA/CA",
        " HDLC"
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "In CSMA/CD, it deals with detection of collision after collision has occurred, whereas CSMA/CA deals with preventing collision. CSMA/CD is abbreviation for Carrier Sensing Multiple Access/Collision detection. CSMA/CA is abbreviation for Carrier Sensing Multiple Access/Collision Avoidance.  These protocols are used for efficient multiple channel access",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Data Link Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
,
{
    "question": "Which of the following are transport layer protocols used in networking?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        " TCP and FTP",
        " UDP and HTTP",
        " TCP and UDP",
        " HTTP and FTP"
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "Both TCP and UDP are transport layer protocol in networking. TCP is an abbreviation for Transmission Control Protocol and UDP is an abbreviation for User Datagram Protocol. TCP is connection oriented whereas UDP is connectionless.",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Transport Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
,
{
    "question": "Which one of the following is a version of UDP with congestion control?",
    "question_img": "",
    "options": [
        "datagram congestion control protocol",
        " stream control transmission protocol",
        " structured stream transport",
        " user congestion control protocol "
        
    ],
    "option_img": [
        "","","",""
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "The datagram congestion control is a transport layer protocol which deals with reliable connection setup, teardown, congestion control, explicit congestion notification, and feature negotiation. It is used in modern day systems where there are really high chances of congestion. The protocol was last updated in the year 2008.",
    "subject": "Computer Networks",
    "topic": "Transport Layer",
    "exam": "GATE CSE",
    "field": "Engineering",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "timeLimit": 60,
    "marks": 1,
    "negativeMarks": -1
}
]